<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Monera-Design Co., Ltd - News</title>
  <updated>2021-08-18T14:35:37+07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Monera-Design Co., Ltd</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/gold-stainless-steel-jewelry</id>
    <published>2021-08-18T14:35:37+07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-18T14:37:52+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/gold-stainless-steel-jewelry"/>
    <title>Gold Stainless Steel Jewelry</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>Gold Stainless Steel Jewelry</h1>
<p>The idea of gold stainless steel might sound a bit strange at first. It need not be. Gold stainless steel jewelry is simply stainless steel jewelry that has a thin layer of gold coating.</p>
<p>This process is often done using an electric current with a tub of gold solution. This process is commonly known as wet plating.</p>
<p>The layer of gold plating can be anywhere from 0.17 to 2.5 microns. A micron is equal to 0.0001 centimeters. The final color you get will vary in color depending on the purity of the gold used to do the plating.</p>
<h2>When Plated Jewelry Is Ideal</h2>
<p>Gold-plated jewelry often has a short lifespan, typically six months to a year. So to extend longevity, it's best to get gold stainless steel pieces for ornaments you do not wear often.</p>
<p>The reason for this is that gold-plated items have very little actual gold on them. This makes them more susceptible to tarnishing and fading. In addition, for metals that are not hypoallergenic, this can expose the wearer to skin irritation.</p>
<p>Stainless steel is hypoallergenic, so this is not something you need to worry about when wearing gold stainless steel.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-R150-B-1500x1500_480x480.jpg?v=1618807352" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<h2>Taking Care Of Your Gold Stainless Steel Ornaments</h2>
<p>While you can get to enjoy your jewelry for about a year without it fading, this does not come without taking some precautions.</p>
<p>For starters, avoid wearing gold stainless steel with other items as these can rub against each other and damage the coating much faster. As much as possible, wear your plated stainless steel on its own.</p>
<p>Secondly, avoid water, chemicals, and make-up coming into direct contact with your plated items as much as possible. If you are a swimmer, for example, the chemicals in a pool can quickly corrode the coating. In such a case, it helps to take off this jewelry before taking a dip. If you forget to do so, ensure to rinse it with plain water as soon as possible and air dry it.</p>
<p>After you have worn your gold-plated stainless steel jewelry, ensure to wipe it down at the end of the day. Use a soft cloth to gently rub its surface up and down to pry away any dirt and debris it might have collected during wear.</p>
<p>If you need a more thorough clean, soak it in warm water and mild dishwashing soap solution. A 10-15 minute soak will loosen any dirt, sweat, and make-up from the jewelry’s surface. You can then gently wash it with a soft cloth and air dry it before putting it in storage.</p>
<p>Again, try and store gold stainless steel jewelry in individual cloth bags to prevent them from scratching each other and possibly getting damaged.</p>
<p>It might also help to take off your jewelry before hitting the gym or engaging in other activities that might cause you to sweat.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-ER1238-B_480x480.jpg?v=1629272106" alt="" style="margin-right: 25.3385px; margin-left: 25.3385px; float: none;"></div>
<h2>One Final Thing…</h2>
<p>Aside from proper care, a sure way to ensure your jewelry remains in top shape for longer is by buying good quality, to begin with. By purchasing from a reputable dealer, you are certain that the jewelry was made under strict conditions to give you the quality you deserve.</p>
<p>Look no further than <a href="http://monera-design.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>Monera jewelry design and manufacturer</span></a> for classy, affordable, high-quality, exquisite fashion accessories for your next buy.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span> </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/can-you-take-a-shower-with-stainless-steel-jewelry</id>
    <published>2021-07-16T14:57:45+07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-16T15:15:50+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/can-you-take-a-shower-with-stainless-steel-jewelry"/>
    <title>Can You Take a Shower With Stainless Steel Jewelry?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>Can You Take a Shower With Stainless Steel Jewelry?</h1>
<p>Stainless steel jewelry is a great option for many for numerous reasons. Key among them is that it's relatively affordable compared to gold, and it's very durable. Stainless steel jewelry also offers a clean, understated finish that can effortlessly go with anything in your wardrobe.</p>
<p>These are some of the qualities that have escalated its popularity in recent years.</p>
<p>However, once you get your jewelry, it's common to wonder about its care regimen and its limitations. For example, a common question asked regarding stainless steel jewelry is how it holds to water.</p>
<h2>Does Stainless Steel Tarnish?</h2>
<p>Before we get into how your stainless steel jewelry will handle water, let’s talk about this metal Vis a Vis tarnishing.</p>
<p>Do stainless steel rings tarnish? What of other stainless steel jewelry items?</p>
<p>The answer to both these questions is no. Good quality stainless steel jewelry will not tarnish. However, you have to consider the grade of stainless steel you are getting before making a purchase. Lower grades can tarnish; good grade stainless steel will not.</p>
<p>The best quality stainless steel is 304, also referred to as 18/10/ or 18/8 respectively, to represent its composition. This means 18% Chromium and 10% Nickel or 18% Chromium and 8% Nickel. The other grade is 316.</p>
<p>Stainless steel also has 2% molybdenum. Molybdenum increases the metals’ resistance to corrosion and acids with chloride ions. This prevents it from rusting.</p>
<h2>Can I shower With Stainless Steel Jewelry?</h2>
<p>Yes, you can. You can safely shower with your stainless steel jewelry and wash your hands with a stainless steel ring without the ornaments getting any major damage.</p>
<p>While water might not cause any damage, harsh chemicals can. Mild shampoos and shower gels are fine, but if you have any corrosive hair chemicals and so on, it might be prudent to take the jewelry off. You can also be sure to rinse it and dry it off properly if you accidentally expose it to harsher chemicals.</p>
<p>What about water with different compositions?</p>
<h2>Stainless Steel in Ocean Water</h2>
<p>You already know the ocean is salty. What you probably don't know is that these levels of salt are not very kind to any metal, stainless steel included.</p>
<p>As gorgeous as your jewelry might be, do not wear it in the ocean. There are also other dissolved substances and inorganic materials that might damage your ornaments. The ocean also has sand that can scratch the jewelry's surface.</p>
<ol>
<li><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/blog_2_480x480.jpg?v=1626422250" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></li>
</ol>
<h2>Stainless Steel in a Pool</h2>
<p>Stainless steel with molybdenum offers some protection against acids and localized corrosion from chloride ions. If you are an active swimmer, it’s important to get jewelry with this compound.</p>
<p>However, you better off taking off your jewelry before diving into a pool to be on the safer side. If you forget to do this, rinse the piece with clean water as soon as possible, and air dry it.</p>
<p> </p>
<h1>Final Word</h1>
<p>Here you have it. You can have your <a href="http://monera-design.com" target="_blank" title="Wholesale stainless steel jewelry " rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>stainless steel jewelry from Monera</span></a> in the shower without degrading it. However, take them off when in the ocean or the swimming pool.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/why-stainless-steel-bracelets-are-the-best-gifts-for-men</id>
    <published>2021-06-21T10:19:01+07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-21T10:21:08+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/why-stainless-steel-bracelets-are-the-best-gifts-for-men"/>
    <title>Why Stainless Steel Bracelets Are The Best Gifts For Men?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>Why Stainless Steel Bracelets Are The Best Gifts For Men</h1>
<p>It's often surprising how a simple piece of jewelry can instantly transform a look and give it the wow factor.</p>
<p>Over the years, bracelets that were once a preserve for the ladies have made their way into the gent's shopping section as well. If you are looking to buy a gift for a special gentleman soon, a stainless steel bracelet should top your list.</p>
<p>Wondering why? Here are five reasons why a steel bracelet is the best gift for a man.</p>
<h2>It's Hypoallergenic</h2>
<p>One thing you want in a gift is safety. Unfortunately, many people are allergic to nickel, a metal commonly alloyed with other jewelry-making metals.</p>
<p>A common advantage of stainless steel is that, unlike gold and silver, it's unlikely to trigger any adverse skin reactions. Good quality pieces will also have a silver finish which also gives you the aesthetic qualities of silver.</p>
<h2>Comfort</h2>
<p>Stainless steel is a light material. Bracelets made from this metal tend to be extremely light to wear, making them comfortable enough for most scenarios.</p>
<p>You would want to give someone something that fits into their life seamlessly, so it's never in their way as they go about their business.</p>
<h2>Easy to Maintain</h2>
<p>It’s always important to find jewelry with an easy maintenance and care routine. Stainless steel bracelets fit the bill.</p>
<p>This will not be jewelry that the recipient will have to get professionally cleaned from time to time, which is advantageous.</p>
<p>A simple dishwashing detergent and warm water solution are often all that is required to keep stainless steel jewelry in tip-top shape. All one needs to do is soak it in this solution before brushing it with a soft-bristled brush to remove dirt and debris.</p>
<p>Over time, if the bracelet begins to lose its luster, a professional cleaner can restore its shine with ease.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/BLG_480x480.jpg?v=1624245611" alt=""></p>
<h2>It maintains Its Looks</h2>
<p>While gold and silver offer a lot in terms of aesthetics, they are also prone to staining.</p>
<p>Stainless steel jewelry has a chromium layer that helps prevent oxidation. Aside from it being her to oxidize and discolor, stainless steel is also resistant to dust.</p>
<p>The metal is also hard to chip.</p>
<p>If you are looking to purchase the perfect bracelet for a man with an active lifestyle, a stainless steel bracelet should be it. Unlike other metal compounds that will look worse for wear in a couple of months, stainless steel jewelry tends to hold its own and maintain its luster and form over time.</p>
<h2>It’s Eco-friendly</h2>
<p>People are increasingly becoming more conscious of the environment and what they can do at an individual level towards sustainably.</p>
<p>If you or the jewelry’s recipient is keen on sustainability, a stainless steel bracelet is a great choice.</p>
<p>This is for two main reasons. The first is that stainless steel is 100% recyclable. The second is that stainless steel jewelry requires minimal energy to produce.</p>
<p> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BR646-art_2_-D_480x480.jpg?v=1624245570" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<h1>Trouble Shopping?</h1>
<p>At Monera Design Co., Ltd, we understand jewelry shopping can be overwhelming. For this reason, we have a comprehensive catalog for you to look at from the comfort of your home.<span style="color: #2b00ff;"> <a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bracelets" target="_blank" title="Stainless Steel Bracelet" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #2b00ff;">Follow this link </a></span>to look at some excellent stainless steel bracelets.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/some-facts-on-stainless-steel-jewelry</id>
    <published>2021-05-31T13:45:07+07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T13:45:08+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/some-facts-on-stainless-steel-jewelry"/>
    <title>Some Facts On Stainless Steel Jewelry</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>Is Stainless Steel Jewelry Safe to Wear?</h1>
<p>Stainless steel is made from at least 10.5% chromium and other alloying compounds. It also contains carbon in quantities of 1.2% or less. These alloying compounds include nickel, niobium, molybdenum, titanium and manganese.</p>
<p>Stainless steel was traditionally found in medical equipment. In recent times, this metal has found itself in jewelry-making for all the stellar qualities it is known to provide to medical equipment.</p>
<h2>Is Stainless Steel Safe to Wear?</h2>
<p>For the most part, yes. Medical grade stainless is extremely safe to wear on the skin. The only issue with stainless steel is the alloys used, their quality and their quantities can cause problems to wearers.</p>
<p>One of the alloys that commonly cause problems is nickel. Nickel is affordable, making it the go-to alloy metal of choice for many jewelers. Unfortunately, many people have a sensitivity to this metal. This often happens when there is 100parts of nickel per million. However, in most countries, the amounts of nickel used in jewelry are highly regulated to ensure end-user safety.</p>
<p>This means that jewelry pieces carrying anything above the healthy amounts are not allowed to retail. 304 stainless steel and 316L surgical steel have extremely low Nickel levels and are often safe to wear even for individuals with a Nickel allergy to enjoy wearing occasionally.</p>
<p>305 stainless steel has 8% Nickel, compared to 10% in 316L Nickel, making it the safest of all stainless steel. </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/products/MNC-ER1260-B_480x480.jpg?v=1622193191" alt=""></p>
<h2>How To Test Genuine Stainless Steel?</h2>
<p>The easiest way to test stainless steel jewelry is using a magnet. Because steel is magnetic, your jewelry should attach to the magnet. If this does not happen, you do not have stainless steel.</p>
<p>The other test is rust. Properly processed stainless steel does not rust. If your jewelry begins showing signs of rust around the edges and whatnot, this might indicate what you have is not stainless steel.</p>
<p>The two final ones are the polish and the tap tests.</p>
<p>For the polish test, wipe the surface of your jewelry with a dry cloth and check to see if you can see your reflection. With stainless steel, you should be able to see your face. If you don't, you probably have a knock-off or other metal like aluminum.</p>
<p>The tap test, on the other hand, requires you to tap the surface of your jewelry with a brass key or a penny. A 'ting' sound indicates stainless steel, while a 'clang' indicates what you have is not actual stainless steel.</p>
<p><strong>Advantages of Stainless Steel Jewelry</strong></p>
<p>The first thing stainless steel has going for it is durability. Unlike some jewelry types that are extremely fragile and require to be worn with caution, stainless steel jewelry is sturdy enough to be worn by the most active people, with minimal damage.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The other is aesthetic value. The shine produced by stainless steel jewelry comes pretty close to that from sterling silver, often at a lower cost.</p>
<p>Lastly, this compound won’t rust or corrode. You can wear it comfortably in any climatic conditions without worrying about damaging it.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>At <span><a href="https://monera-design.com/">Monera Jewelry Design and Manufacture</a></span>, we exclusively create a wide array of jewelry pieces using 316L stainless steel. You can trust our products for quality, longevity and safety.</p>
<p> <a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/hot-stainless-steel-jewelry-trends-for-2021</id>
    <published>2021-04-19T11:49:20+07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T11:51:41+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/hot-stainless-steel-jewelry-trends-for-2021"/>
    <title>Hot Stainless Steel Jewelry Trends For 2021</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An unconventional metal whose popularity is growing in leaps in the fashion industry is, without a doubt, stainless steel. The love for this metal has largely been propelled by its excellent attributes as it is tough, durable, and resistant to rust. This has further been propelled by the bright silver finish that gives it a distinctive appeal. It is also a safe option if you are after a jewelry metal that is least likely to cause bad skin reactions. Even as more people opt for stainless steel jewelry for its exceptional properties, here are the hottest trends that you should be part of:</span></p>
<h2><b>Stainless Steel Rings</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since stainless steel is very strong and this makes it an excellent material for rings. The defining strength of stainless steel rings is that they are tough enough to withstand regular wear without losing their shine. When looking for</span><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-rings"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale stainless steel rings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, you will be captivated by the fantastic designs and style options available. From signet stone rings and laser-cut rings to minimalist rings with chains and layered square-shaped rings, all preferences are factored in the creation of these beautiful masterpieces.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-rings" title="Steel Rings"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-rings</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-R150-B-1500x1500_480x480.jpg?v=1618807352" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><b>Stainless Steel Chains</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No wardrobe is ever complete without having several chains, as these jewelry pieces are the perfect accessory for most outfits. Whether you want to compliment an official dress as you go for that meeting or you are after a playful touch to your outfit for a night out, stainless steel chains will always come in handy. A simple solution to finding a piece that everyone will love is to invest in our</span><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-chains"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale stainless steel chains</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This will give you the flexibility of having a diverse collection that will suit all needs.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-chains" title="Steel Chains"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-chains</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-C064_2_-A-1500x1500_480x480.jpg?v=1618807294" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><b>Stainless Steel Bracelets</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have you been keeping tabs on the leading fashion figures and celebrities? One thing you are bound to notice is that they are likely to be rocking bracelets. This is a current hot trend that cannot be wished away, and you can always capitalize on it by investing in</span><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bracelets"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale stainless steel bracelets</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. A winning edge for these bracelets starts right from their broad color selection to stylish finishes that make them a must-have.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bracelets" title="Steel Bracelet"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bracelets</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BR540-A-1500x1500_480x480.jpg?v=1618807601" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><b>Stainless Steel Bangles</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A suitable alternative to bracelets is bangles, the primary reason why they are part of the current hot trends. The beauty and shine of our</span><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bangles"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale stainless steel bangles</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> created by seasoned designers are bound to give you the thrills. You will further appreciate the ease of pairing different bangles for a captivating look by playing around with their sizes, colors, and designs.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bangles" title="Steel Bangle"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bangles</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BG254-A-1500x1500_480x480.jpg?v=1618807635" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<h2><b>Stainless Steel Necklaces</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The charm of our</span><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-necklaces"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">wholesale stainless steel necklaces</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has been the top reason why they are always in demand. They are the perfect addition to any jewelry collection as there is never a limit to how many necklaces you can ever own. There are a wide variety of color choices and designs, from simplistic pieces for formal wear to captivating long pieces with beautiful pendants for casual wear.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-necklaces" title="Steel Necklace"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-necklaces</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/555-P006-Amazon-A_480x480.jpg?v=1618807681" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/is-stainless-steel-jewelry-hypoallergenic</id>
    <published>2021-03-11T13:51:36+07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-11T13:55:03+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/is-stainless-steel-jewelry-hypoallergenic"/>
    <title>Is Stainless Steel Jewelry Hypoallergenic?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1><span>Is Stainless Steel Jewelry Hypoallergenic?</span></h1>
<p>When you have sensitive skin, taking care of yourself is quite challenging as you have to evaluate every item before you use it. Mainly, you are limited in the type of jewelry you can put on, as the direct contact of these fashion accessories often results in bad allergies. All the itching, red, and swollen skin is never pleasant, and you are always better off avoiding situations that lead to these problems. This brings us to the big question - can you wear stainless steel jewelry without it reacting with your sensitive skin?</p>
<h2><span>A look at stainless steel jewelry and its formation</span></h2>
<p>If you have sensitive skin, then the metals that primarily lead to an allergic reaction are nickel, copper, and zinc. Nickel is the worst of the three, as studies have shown that it is the most reactive to people with sensitive skin. This means that you always need to go for the nickel-free options whenever you are shopping for jewelry, as they are likely to be hypoallergenic. Sadly, nickel is widely used when making metal alloys, given its excellent properties since it hardens metals such as silver and gold.</p>
<p>When it comes to the formation of stainless steel, it is a similar scenario as the preferred metals for creating this alloy is nickel. Nevertheless, this metal compound is at times made of other metals such as chromium, titanium, carbon, and iron. In such cases, the stainless steel will have low or negligible nickel levels, making it have excellent hypoallergenic properties. This is why today, you find the term ‘nickel-free stainless steel’ is widely used when marketing stainless steel jewelry that does not contain any percentage of nickel.</p>
<h2 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-R432-model_1_-A-1500x1500_480x480.jpg?v=1615445683" alt=""></span></h2>
<h2><span>Should I purchase stainless steel jewelry if I have sensitive skin?</span></h2>
<p>The most straightforward answer to this question is –it depends.</p>
<p>You are probably wondering, what does it depend on? Well, firstly, you need to consider the type of stainless steel that the jewelry is made from. Secondly, you need to know how sensitive your skin is to metals used to make this alloy. If you are highly sensitive to even the lowest exposure of these metals, then you need to avoid any jewelry that contains any trace of these allergens.</p>
<p>Generally, the rule of thumb for anyone with sensitive skin is to settle for surgical-grade stainless steel alloys. The best grade widely used for making jewelry is the 316L stainless steel, as it is almost 100% free of nickel. This is a giant leap from most stainless steel grades that contain up to 10% nickel and would pose a severe risk if you have sensitive skin.</p>
<h2><span>Why choose 316L stainless steel jewelry for sensitive skin</span></h2>
<p>In the fashion industry, the 316L stainless steel is widely known as hypoallergenic stainless steel. The reason behind this is simple – this stainless steel alloy does not contain any metal that widely causes allergic reactions. All the metals used to make the 316L stainless steel, namely chromium and iron, are relatively stable and non-reactive. The best part is that this alloy does not rust even when exposed to damp environments, and you will never have to worry about it rusting over time.</p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry" title="Wholesale Stainless Steel Jewelry "><span>https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry</span></a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/316l-stainless-steel-jewelry-a-perfection-taken-too-far</id>
    <published>2021-01-13T17:31:55+07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T17:33:46+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/316l-stainless-steel-jewelry-a-perfection-taken-too-far"/>
    <title>316l Stainless Steel Jewelry - A Perfection Taken too Far</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Not too many people pay attention to gold jewelry products as we use to think; hence, stainless steel Jewelry is still a thing. According to Market Watch®, stainless steel jewelry is expected to reach a top high in 2025; evidence of stainless steel jewelry wearer renewed loyalty. The increase in the stainless steel jewelry market is also attributed to the newer technologies that have been making their way to the industry every now and then. These technological innovations have given way for more fascinating designs that have thrilled the fancy of an average wearer, hence, the renewed loyalty.</p>
<p>This new increase is witnessed in countries like the USA, Europe, Japan, China, India, and Southeast Asia. Recently, Thailand joined the league of top silver steel jewelry producers: thanks to the devoted efforts of some visionary companies like 316L Stainless Steel Jewelry who has spent time, effort, and resources coming out with new ways of making men and women look radiant through the production of quality stainless steel jewelry. It will be fair to note that what makes jewelry stand out is not the material used but the design and the craft put into it, and 316L Stainless Steel Jewelry knows the best way to go about it.</p>
<p>As we mentioned earlier, there are other stainless steel jewelry companies (including stainless steel bangles wholesale companies). Still, the uniqueness of 316L Stainless Steel Jewelry products comes with the amount of time spent producing them, thus, the durability. Unlike other silver jewelry manufacturing companies, this company gives more than finishing to their jewelry. More reason its outcome always stands out.</p>
<p>Again, their designs are second to none; mere looking at them makes you understand the power of creativity and style. For people who like to personalize their designs, there is also room for customized production of any design; all you need do is come up with it (your design). But more interestingly, the company has a way of even suggesting some awesome designs to these customers who can't find their design even on the "wholesale 316L Stainless Steel Jewelry" section. Below are some of the interesting products lines you can find in their catalog:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Steel Jewelry</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>In the "steel jewelry," you get to find six other subsections to find different steel items ranging from bracelets, rings, necklaces, and pendants.</p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry" target="_blank" title="Stainless Steel Jewelry" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry</a></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Silver Jewelry</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>This is where you get assorted silver jewelry of all designs and shapes. Some of its subcategories include silver rings, silver earrings, silver necklaces, silver bracelets, and men's silver jewelry. Note, this is where the male folks are allowed to explore more fashion jewelry.</p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/silver-jewelry" target="_blank" title="Silver Jewelry" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://monera-design.com/collections/silver-jewelry</a></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Fashion Jewelry</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>This is where you get all types of fashion jewelry you need: men, women, young adults, etc. This is it. Some of the categories include fashion rings, earrings, and necklaces. You also get to see the most colorful jewelry in their hundreds, all you need to us to make the right choices.</p>
<p>Finally, stainless steel jewelry has always been seen as a good product, but what makes it stand out is the kind of design and treatment given to it, and 316l Stainless Steel Jewelry is always there to provide you with nothing but the finest.</p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/fashion-jewelry" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Fashion Jewelry" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://monera-design.com/collections/fashion-jewelry</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/what-is-stainless-steel-jewelry-is-it-good-or-not</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T14:36:49+07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T14:37:55+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/what-is-stainless-steel-jewelry-is-it-good-or-not"/>
    <title>What is Stainless Steel Jewelry? Is it Good or Not?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>What is stainless steel jewelry? Is it good or not?</strong></p>
<p>While most of us are used to sterling silver jewelry and gold, we haven't always had experience with stainless steel jewelry.  However, there seems to be a lot flooding the market in recent years, so why stainless steel jewelry and is it safe? Does it rust or tarnish?  How do you care for it?  These are very good questions that we would like to tackle today.  </p>
<p>Stainless steel jewelry is made from stainless steel.  There are different grades of stainless steel that vary all over the place.  Stainless steel is made for all kinds of applications and jewelry happens to be one of them.  The jewelry-grade stainless steel is hard, it doesn't rust and it doesn't tarnish.  This makes stainless steel a really good material for making jewelry as it is easy to care for.  Stainless steel is very stable too.  This means that it can be worn in all kinds of applications from people working on cars to taking a shower and swimming without any effects.  The color of stainless steel is a platinum silver color that is simply beautiful.  Many people enjoy the color of stainless steel as it is a darker gray than that of Sterling Silver.  </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNR-229T-art_480x480.jpg?v=1600266181" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Affordable stainless steel jewelry.</strong></p>
<p>Stainless steel is not a precious metal so that it is not a super expensive material.  However, it is very durable and it can outperform more of the precious materials on its stability.  It also can be worn all the time and will not change colors or the finish wears off.  We offer a vast assortment of stainless steel jewelry to choose from.  Take a look at the stainless steel rings, earrings, bracelets, and more.  Stainless steel can be made into just about any type of jewelry possible and it takes to enamel and holds stones perfectly.  </p>
<p>Stainless steel jewelry, like any jewelry, can be simple and sleek to something frilly and girly.  You can wear your stainless steel jewelry everywhere you go and not worry about tarnish.  Should you get your stainless steel jewelry dirty by gardening or working on a car, simply use an old toothbrush and clean it up with some soap and water.  You really have not seen any other metal in jewelry like this.  It is so simple to care for and you can wear it for years.  Because of this many men's wedding bands are made from Stainless steel as it can hold up the test of time.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-P942-art-B_480x480.jpg?v=1605252899" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p><strong>Stainless steel jewelry for those with active lifestyles.</strong></p>
<p>Whether you like girly and fancy or something simple, Stainless steel jewelry is a perfect choice.  If you are hard on your jewelry and have an active lifestyle then this is the material all your jewelry should be made of.  The durability and ability to be worn day in and day out allowing you to put on your jewelry and be done with it.  No need to pamper your jewelry or worry.  Stainless steel is perfect for kids as well as adults and it is affordable. If you are looking for affordable jewelry that lasts, why not try Stainless Steel Jewelry?</p>
<p>Visit Our Steel Collection :</p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry">https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-jewelry</a></p>
<p><span>Visit Our Silver Collection: </span></p>
<p><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/silver-jewelry">https://monera-design.com/collections/silver-jewelry</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/which-is-better-sterling-silver-or-stainless-steel-jewelry</id>
    <published>2020-10-15T16:03:05+07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-15T16:05:58+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/which-is-better-sterling-silver-or-stainless-steel-jewelry"/>
    <title>Which Is Better: Sterling Silver or Stainless Steel Jewelry?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1 style="margin: 0in;"><span style="color: #0e101a; font-weight: normal;">Which Is Better: Sterling Silver or Stainless Steel Jewelry?<p></p></span></h1>
<p> </p>
<p>If you are a big fan of jewelry, you probably have had this debate in your head already. </p>
<p>When it comes to jewelry, the great divide is about gold vs. silver. While being a silver lover edges you closer to your final choice,</p>
<p>You still need to choose between the two big wigs: sterling silver and stainless steel.</p>
<p>Which one of these is best?</p>
<p>Here, read more on what each is, the differences, and the best pick.</p>
<h2>316L Stainless Steel vs. 925 Sterling Silver</h2>
<p>These two metals confuse most people because they share a common physical property; both have a shiny, silvery finish. </p>
<p>This aside, the two are very different. </p>
<p>Stainless steel consists of iron and chromium. At times, there are traces of nickel. When oxygen mixes with chromium, a transparent film is formed. This film is what protects the steel from rusting. </p>
<p>The steel used in making jewelry differs from the one used in construction and is also known as surgical stainless steel. The result is a durable, timeless, monochromatic look.  </p>
<p>Stainless Steel Jewelry Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>More affordable compared to sterling silver jewelry</li>
<li>Beautiful, mirror finish</li>
<li>Durable</li>
<li>Hard to dent</li>
<li>It does not rust, meaning its less likely to lose its glossy appearance</li>
</ul>
<p>Stainless Steel Jewelry Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>It’s very hard, which also makes resizing difficult. </li>
</ul>
<p>Sterling silver is not pure silver, but silver with another metal.  </p>
<p>Sterling silver means 92.5 % of silver blended with a 7.5 % copper alloy. The number 925 or sterling is often stamped on jewelry to indicate that the piece is made of sterling silver.</p>
<p>Sterling Silver Jewelry Pros: </p>
<ul>
<li>It has an attractive, matte, classy finish</li>
<li>It can be molded easily, which explains the variety of designs jewelry creators can come up with</li>
<li>You can get stones included in it</li>
</ul>
<p>Sterling Silver Jewelry Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>It tarnishes with time</li>
<li>it lacks the new jewelry look and shines</li>
<li>It can be dented</li>
<li>it’s often costlier than stainless steel</li>
</ul>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Which Is Best?</h2>
<p>The stainless steel vs. sterling silver debate is unlikely to end any day soon. Often, it boils down to preference. </p>
<p>There are, however, good reasons why stainless steel seems to be the preferred option for most customers.  </p>
<p>Its shiny look, affordability, and easy to clean properties make stainless steel jewelry very appealing.</p>
<p>The other significant deciding factor is that stainless steel is hypoallergenic. Wearers enjoy the freedom that comes with wearing their jewelry without the risk of skin irritation. Stainless steel jewelry allows you to enjoy your pieces year-round, safely.</p>
<p>The third is that it’s extremely easy to maintain. A quick wash with warm soapy water and a firm polish is all you need to keep your jewelry looking brand new. </p>
<h2>Looking For a Supplier?</h2>
<p>At Monera, we understand how important it is for jewelry retail businesses such as yours to partner with a reputable supplier with a limited supply of designs for your clients to choose from. </p>
<p>Monera is a leading Thailand-based jewelry designer and manufacturer renowned for exquisite stainless steel jewelry designs. </p>
<p>We have become synonymous with fast delivery and excellent customer service for our clients. Click <a href="http://monera-design.com">here </a>to join our esteemed network of jewelry resellers. </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/top-5-most-popular-types-of-stainless-steel-316l-jewelry</id>
    <published>2020-09-16T21:40:40+07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-16T21:40:41+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/top-5-most-popular-types-of-stainless-steel-316l-jewelry"/>
    <title>Top 5 Most Popular Types of Stainless Steel 316L Jewelry</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Selling Jewelry is a great way to earn an income, whether as a full time job or an additional income earner. <br>When you think about it, this is a business you can do online or in a small business premise. <br>If you have store space dealing with other products, these take up very little space. This means you can have a wide array of jewelry without eating up a significant part of your store’s space. </p>
<p><br><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-pendants" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Steel Pendants</strong></span></a><br>The best thing about carrying a pendant collection is that they are unisex, meaning you have a broader client base.<br>Besides this, pendants are great gifting items. With good marketing, you can get numerous clients coming for pendants around holidays, birthdays, and anniversaries.<br>You can also do some value addition by identifying a jewelry engraver. You can then offer engraving services to your customers to make the pieces more intimate. </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/n204_480x480.jpg?v=1600265928" alt="" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-bracelets"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Steel Bracelets</span></strong></a><br>Monera Designs a wide array of bracelets to suit even the most discerning customer. <br>Our bracelets are easy on the eye, high quality, and with good, durable clasps.<br>You can get these in chain, roped, and bangle designs. Your clients are unlikely to miss a design bracelet they like in a color they will love.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BR154-art_480x480.jpg?v=1600266064" alt="" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-rings"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Steel Rings</span></strong></a><br>Rings have come a long way. Once confined to engagements ceremonies and weddings, rings have morphed into ornamental pieces fashion-conscious people can't do without.<br>Because of their small size, you can stock a large number of these at your store, form cocktail rings to heart glass designs to men’s statement rings. <br>Some of the rings in our collection have a wide girth to allow engraving should a customer require it. <br>You can get both formal and casual cuts. You have a choice of silver, rose gold and zirconia. Some designs also come in two tones. </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNR-229T-art_480x480.jpg?v=1600266181" alt="" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-earrings"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Steel Earrings</span></strong></a><br>Earrings are considered minimalist jewelry because people who don't like jewelry much still tend to wear earrings every often.<br>We manufacture hypoallergenic earrings to ensure that clients with metal allergies are not left behind. <br>The earring line has everything from rhinestones to simple, plain options.  Whatever your customers desire, whether danglers, hoops, or studs, our collection is guaranteed to deliver.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-ER732-art_480x480.jpg?v=1600266263" alt="" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br><a href="https://monera-design.com/collections/steel-necklaces"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Steel Necklaces</span></strong></a><br>Neck pieces are still a simple way to elevate any outfit. <br>This should be a staple for your business as well because they are unisex. <br>For your clientele, you can stock thee in steel and several other colors as well. There are also plain necklaces, as well as ones with charms. You can start with an assorted mix of necklaces as you monitor purchasing trends and learn what your clients prefer.  </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-N264-art_3_480x480.jpg?v=1600267121" alt="" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br>Get yours from the experts With 20 years in the business, we are alive to what it takes to make a business thrive. For this reason, we endeavor to remain fashion-forward on all our designs.</p>
<p>This aside, Monera Design is built on a culture of customer eccentricity. We understand our pivotal role in your store is success, and we strive to deliver.<br>If you are looking to get into jewelry wholesale or retail, the leading stainless steel supplier from Thailand, Monera, can guarantee an array of designs and fast delivery globally.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/buying-wholesale-jewelry-for-sale-some-tips-to-help-you-find-the-best-supplier</id>
    <published>2020-08-22T22:27:00+07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-22T22:31:56+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/buying-wholesale-jewelry-for-sale-some-tips-to-help-you-find-the-best-supplier"/>
    <title>Buying Wholesale Jewelry for sale? Some Tips to help you find the best Supplier !</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>One thing you will learn as you settle into your entrepreneurial journey is the number of decisions you will have to make on the day-to-day. <br>The good news is, it gets easier. <br>If you take certain actions to put the right systems in place from the beginning, you will find that your workload will become lighter and your business will run much more smoothly than anticipated. <br>In the jewelry business, your choice of supplier can make or break your business. This makes it extremely important to find the best fit for you. </p>
<p><br>1. How do you go about this? Here are five tips to get you started. <br>Network Business calls for a lot of networking. <br>By joining professional networks and groups that bring together people in your field, you learn and hear a lot of first-hand information. This will include who the best and most affordable suppliers are.<br>You can also ask directly for referrals if you know other jewelry sellers in your locale. </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BR470-art_large.jpg?v=1598110197" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p>2. Shop Around<br>Resist from settling for the first supplier you find online or are referred to. <br>You often find that with a little more effort, you can find a supplier with better prices, processes, and policies.<br>Keep in mind that comparing different companies is not only aimed at finding one with the lowest prices. Delivery times, customer service, return policies and product quality are just as important as cost. <br>With this in mind, find 3-5 good companies and then proceed into in-depth research. </p>
<p>3. Research<br>The internet has made it a lot easier to find information about virtually any topic. <br>When you have shortlisted a few suppliers to look into, the next step is to do more research.<br>Reading reviews is one way to dig deeper. Look up the suppliers online and see what other people are saying about them, their products and their customer service ratings. <br>Chances are, if many other people have had positive experiences with a particular company, you will too.</p>
<p>4. Try the Manufacturer<br>Instead of getting your products from a supplier or wholesale, you can try purchasing directly from the manufacturer. <br>By buying straight from the manufacturer, you get to sample their entire range of products. It’s also often cheaper to buy directly from the source. This is because everyone in between marks-up the price, gradually increasing the initial cost. </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BR275-art_3_large.jpg?v=1598110238" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p>5. Wide Payment Options<br>Because you have a lot of moving bits to handle as a businessman, you want most processes to be as simple as possible.<br>As you vet jewelers, also look at the mode of payment they provide. You want to pick a company with as many various options as possible because then you are unlikely to get stuck while trying to make payments.<br>Monera Jewelry Design and Manufacturer, for example, allows its customers to pay via credit cards, online money platforms and make bank transfers.  </p>
<p>6. Take Your Time<br>As eager as you might be to get your jewelry shop up and running, you should take the time to think through and thoroughly research your supplier choice. <br>With nine years in the business, we at Monera Jewelry Designs have supported businesses like yours by designing and supplying affordable all over the world.<br>If you are looking for speedy delivery, quality products, and excellent customer service, contact us here and start your business on the right footing!</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BG269-art_large.jpg?v=1598110302" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/stainless-steel-jewelry-for-men</id>
    <published>2020-07-12T17:32:00+07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-12T17:34:10+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/stainless-steel-jewelry-for-men"/>
    <title>Stainless Steel Jewelry for Men</title>
    <author>
      <name>Fon Monera</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong></strong>Here at MONERA DESIGN, we provide forefront modern men's stainless steel jewelry. Whether to treat yourself or surprise a loved one, our masculine jewelry selection is one you can fully trust to give you superior modern fashion and style – with our vast collection; the choice is all yours. Shop from us today and get the quality masculine touch to whatever outfit you choose. Also, importantly, we decided to provide info for you on essential things to know before investing in wholesale stainless steel for men and maybe for women too.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-R906-blog_grande.jpg?v=1594549741" alt="Stainless steel jewelry for Men" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"> </p>
<p><strong>What to know about stainless steel for men</strong></p>
<p> The steadily increasing price of precious metals like diamond, gold, silver, and stainless steel jewelry has further increased the desire for the fashionistas to demand them. It provides aesthetic appeal in a radiating manner. Stainless steel jewelry might not be one of the most expensive of all precious metals - as a matter of fact - but it still carries a high rate of demand, especially among men. Generally, we might assume that people buy stainless steel for men just for fashion appeal, same as we might think for women, but it is also known to be a worthwhile investment when purchased in wholesale quantity.</p>
<p> <strong>Why invest in wholesale stainless steel jewelry for men?</strong></p>
<p> Unlike some other precious metal, the nature of stainless steel makes it an excellent option for accessories and jewelry making. Given the high cost of metals like gold, platinum, or silver, stainless steel is famously known for its low cost relative to others and a high level of aesthetic appeal. </p>
<p> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-P937-blog_grande.jpg?v=1594549761" alt="Stainless steel jewelry for Men" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p><strong>Stainless steel metal is known for:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Low reactivity</li>
<li>Long-Lasting</li>
<li>Corrosion Resistant.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>What to note while purchasing Stainless Steel jewelry for men?</strong></p>
<p> Listed here are factors to keep in mind while buying wholesale stainless steel jewelry for men:</p>
<p><strong>Quality</strong>: it is highly essential to consider the quality of the stainless steel jewelry for men before investing in it. Just women, lots of men have sensitive skin that may react to pieces of jewelry crafted from 316L stainless steel. There are several fashion pieces of jewelry to opt for, as this particular alloy contains a high amount of chromium and a minimal portion of nickel and carbon. The 319L type of steel is mainly for making high-end luxury jewelry. </p>
<p><strong>Types of Stainless steel:</strong> there are over 150 types of stainless steel. Each of them serves a particular intention, such as the surgical implants in dentistry, the decorative shield used for building roofs, jewelry making, etc. Designers use the 304 and 302 stainless steel generally for creating fashion jewelry. Though it is suitable for external wear, it is not so advisable to use as piercing jewelry, because of its high level of nickel. Nickel can stain the skin.</p>
<p><strong>Comfort:</strong> when we choose the type of jewelry to buy, we should assess the comfort or discomfort it could bring. Check for points or burs on the surface, check for rough edges contacting the skin. There should be no seams or unevenness.</p>
<p><strong>Cost</strong>: the cost of stainless steel jewelry should be considered. It is merely advisable to invest more in the best quality of stainless steel, be it for men or women. Also to watch out for is the stainless steel design element, size, etc.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><em>We are looking Forward to have your wholesale orders. Good Luck!</em></strong></p>
<p><span> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/MNC-BR530-blog_grande.jpg?v=1594549752" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/how-to-clean-stainless-steel-jewelry</id>
    <published>2020-03-20T14:35:00+07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-23T12:08:33+07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://monera-design.com/blogs/news/how-to-clean-stainless-steel-jewelry"/>
    <title>How to Clean Stainless Steel Jewelry ?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shlomi Balali</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>When looking at how to clean stainless steel jewelry, you find there is some great advice out there.  Stainless steel jewelry is actually really very rugged and can be cleaned in a variety of ways.  When you are preparing to clean your stainless steel jewelry be sure to take the jewelry off.  This will allow you to get at it better but also protects your skin from the substances that you are using to clean it with.  There are a lot of great benefits to wearing and having stainless steel jewelry such as it is one of the best materials for those that have allergies to the various metals. </p>
<p>When looking up how to clean stainless steel jewelry you need to keep in mind that this metal is also very hard.  This means that it is not easily scratched or ruined by abrasive cleaners.  However, we don't recommend abrasive cleaners, unless you absolutely need them.  Most of the time when you are cleaning stainless steel jewelry you are simply looking to clean off the dirt and grime that comes with wearing the jewelry, or you might be looking to clean it after it has been sitting awhile. Neither of these options will require abrasive cleaners. </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/Howto2.jpg?v=1584689686" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Stainless steel doesn't tarnish.</strong></p>
<p>Another amazing trait of stainless steel jewelry is the fact that it doesn't tarnish or rust.  This allows for this type of jewelry to be worn at all times and it really doesn't need to be removed while swimming or showering either.  You should remove your jewelry at all times when you are doing crafting or things that might get paint or other substances on the jewelry to simply protect it.  Like your clothing, your jewelry needs to be protected during certain activities.  </p>
<p>If you are looking for an inexpensive way to clean your stainless steel jewelry, we would recommend getting some baking soda.  Baking soda is great for capturing odors in your fridge and it acts well as a cleaner as well.  All you need is an inexpensive box of baking soda and water to get the job done.  Mix the water and baking soda together to form a bit of a paste.  You can simply use your hands to rub it onto the jewelry but some prefer to use an old toothbrush. </p>
<p>Scrub the jewelry gently until clean.  Once clean, simply rinse the piece of jewelry underwater to rinse away any remaining baking soda.  You can then wipe the jewelry off with a soft towel or napkin to remove any access water.  Be sure to lay it out to dry as well.  This will ensure that all the extra water is gone before putting it away.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/Howto1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1584940009" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Stainless Steel Jewelry Cleaning Kits</strong></p>
<p>If you want to get a little fancier, there are some stainless steel jewelry cleaning kits out there as well.  This allows you to clean the jewelry a little more in-depth.  However, these kits look fancy, they really do about the same job as the baking soda method.  Some will come with a polishing cloth that works basically in the same way as the cloth above as well.</p>
<p>When you are looking to clean your stainless steel jewelry, keep in mind that you are working with one of the hardest metals in which jewelry is made from.  This allows you a little more leeway on what substances you use to clean the metal.  You can also simply use commonly found household cleaning substances as well.  Cleaning your jewelry with a window cleaner or glass cleaner, for example, would be a fine option as well.  Vinegar is also another cleaner that many uses to clean their stainless steel jewelry too.  </p>
<p>An ultrasonic jewelry cleaner might be just the thing if your stainless steel jewelry is very intricate.  This is a machine that is made to clean jewelry.  The solution that you choose to use in the machine can be made for ultrasonic jewelry cleaners or you can simply use glass cleaner.  This is a very effective way to get down in the cracks and rhinestones should you have more details.</p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/Howto4_1024x1024.jpg?v=1584940095" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Common household items to clean stainless steel.</strong></p>
<p>Another great way to clean stainless steel jewelry is with toothpaste.  The mild abrasion is okay for your enamel.  This means that it is not super abrasive but very effective.  To clean, simply rub the toothpaste on the item with either your fingers or a toothbrush.  Rinse when done and pat dry.  Before putting the jewelry back on, you will need to let it sit out for a bit to completely dry.  </p>
<p>For a higher polish to your stainless steel jewelry, you can use a polishing cloth that will help bring out the shine in the jewelry piece. </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0321/7932/3012/files/Howto3_1024x1024.jpg?v=1584940072" alt=""></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
